

MATIAS GIMENEZ Frontend Developer



Profile

I'm a front-end oriented Web Designer and Da Vinci School graduate (2010) who has worked for various high traffic websites, most notably MercadoLibre and DeAutos, where I gained significant first-hand experience in UI/UX development, with equal emphasis on performance and code semantics.

Since 2010, I have worked as a freelancer, developping sites and applications web meeting tight, high-pressure deadlines while ensuring consistent operation.

I am also employed of R/GA Buenos Aires in where we work in contact with offices of differents countries developing web-apps for multiple brands.

My passion for technology extends far beyond the day-to-day demands of my work: I keep a constant eye on emerging trends in the field, so that I'm always updated on the latest advances, with the goal of ensuring that the quality and scope of my work are always expanding.

Skills

Semantic HTML 5	UX / UI Development	PHP
CSS 3 / COMPASS	DOM / AJAX / JSON	My Sql
Vanilla Javascript	Grunt / Gulp	Photoshop
jQuery / jQuery UI	WPO	Illustrator
Responsive Web Design	APIs	Fireworks
Progressive Enhancement	GIT	Scrum

Experience

R/GA

08/2016-Current

Software Engineer, Web Platforms

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3 / COMPASS
- Vanilla JavaScript / ES6
- ReactJS
- Angular 1
- jQuery
- Handlebars JADE
- Frontend Improvements Google Apis
- Grunt / Gulp • Responsive Web Design
- JBoss
- GIT

Eulas

05/2015-07/2016

Frontend Developer UI/UX Semantic HTML5

- CSS3 / COMPASS
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- Handlebars
- Frontend Improvements Google Apis
- Grunt
- Responsive Web Design
- JBoss
- GIT

DeAutos

01/2015-05/2015

Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5 • CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery JS Frameworks
- Frontend Improvements • WPO (Web Performance Optimization)
- Grunt / Gulp
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT

Mercadolibre Frontend Developer UI/UX

08/2012-01/2015

- Semantic HTML5 • CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- Chico UI (JS Framework)
- Components & Libraries Development Progressive Enhancement
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT
- · Grails / Groovy Frontend Meetups

06/2011-08/2012

Web Implementer

8a Marketing Comunicacion y Diseño

Semantic HTML CSS

- jQuery / jQuery UI • PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql
- Newsletters

Joptiwebs Freelance Development

2010-Current

• Corporative Sites, Institutional, Drupal Development.

- Semantic HTML • CSS / CSS3 / SASS
- JS / jQuery / jQuery UI PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql

Education

Designer & Manager Web sites oriented programming

Escuela Multimedial Da Vinci

03/2008-08/2010

03/2004-08/2005

1997-2002

• HTML - XHTML / CSS 2.1 • Javascript / Jquery

• Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash.

- PHP5 MVC / Doctrine Framework / Zend Framework
- MySQL
- WAMP

Universidad Tecnologica Nacional **Technician in Programming**

- Approved subjects: 11/20. • Structure of computer systems, Features OS
- Computer Security (Antivirus, Firewall, Spy, Spam, etc.) Maintain an optimal PC.
- Structure of a PC, Micropocesadores, Memories, Peripherals.
- C & C++

Technical School Reconquista de BsAs. (High School)

Computer technician • C & C++

- Visual Basic
- Fox Pro